# Sushant Kumar Software Engineer

Over 1.5 year of overall experience in web development with emphasis on skills like Angular JS (1.x), Angular (7.x), Angular Material, HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, JSON, Node JS, Bootstrap, ASP.Net C#, MySQL, MS SQL, Oracle DB, etc.

# **Experience**

Jan 2015 -Feb 2015

**Software Engineering Intern** 

Bharat Heavy Electricals Limited

 Website Development and Web Technologies such as HTML/HTML5, CSS, JS, jQuery, Bootstrap

Jul 2015 -Aug 2015 **Software Engineering Intern** 

Bharat Heavy Electricals Limited

ASP.NET and Oracle Database Web Based Applications

Jan 2017 -Sep 2017 **Software Engineering Intern** 

Plankton Solutions Pvt Ltd

• Web Applications using Angular JS(1.x), Angular Material

Oct 2017 present **Software Engineer** 

Plankton Solutions Pvt Ltd

• Web technologies such as Angular (7.x), Angular Material, Node JS, etc.

# **Education**

Apr 2010 -Mar 2011 Class X - CBSE-AISSE

CGPA 9.8

92.2%

Distinction in all subjects, 10/10 in Mathematics

Apr 2012 -Mar 2013 Class XII CBSE-AISSCE

• Distinction in all subjects, 87% in Mathematics, 96% in Computer Science

Aug 2013 -Jun 2017

**B.E. in Computer Science and Engineering** 

69% (First Class)

94% in Mathematics in 4th semester.

# **Projects**

### **Application pool for Telecom Major**

Developed SIM replacement and User Authentication and Authorization web app for a major telecom company using *Angular JS* (1.x) and *Bootstrap*.

# **Service Chat-bot**

Developed chat-bot using *IBM Watson Assistant* (formerly IBM Watson Conversation) as conversation handler, *Angular JS (1.x)* for front-end and *Node JS* for application server.

#### **HR Analytics Tool**

Developed analytics application for recruitment prediction and present employees' analytics in collaboration with Societe Generale using *Angular JS* (1.x), *Chart JS*, *C3 JS*, etc.

## Appointment Scheduler and supporting app pool

Developed application pool for appointment scheduling and all the supporting configuration sub-applications such as slots, teams, holidays, etc. using *Angular (7.x)*, *Angular Material*.

## Control system for Video analytics system

Developed control-system for a video analytics project to download/upload control-sets and submit control-sets for training using Angular (7.x), Angular Material.

## **Personal Info**

#### Residence

Bangalore, Karnataka, India

#### E-mail

sushant.kum96@gmail.com

#### Mobile

+91 97408 95495

#### Website

http://sushantk.com

#### Date of birth

11 Jan 1996

### **Skills**

Angular JS (1.x)

Angular (7.x)

••••

Angular Material

Node JS

Twitter Bootstrap

W3.CSS

••••

JQuery and JQuery UI

••••

ASP.Net C#

VM/Server Deployment on AWS and GCP

••••

**IBM Watson Assistant** 

MySQL

MS-SQL

Oracle DB